## **DATA ANALYST**

A highly motivated data analyst with strong attention to detail and 10+ years' experience in worldwide market-leading companies. Proficient in SQL and relational databases. Experienced in analyzing large amounts of data, preparing easy-to-understand reports, and providing insights for stakeholders. Excellent written and verbal communication skills with the ability to find approach to various stakeholders.

## Skills

- Data analysis, analytical mindset
- SQL, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server
- Tableau
- Python, Pandas, Jupyter Notebook

- Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket
- Problem-solving, communication
- Agile Certified Practitioner
- Continuous learning

## **Professional experience**

<u>HeadHunter</u> (#2 most visited job and employment website in the world as of September 2022)

Moscow, Russia

**Program Management Office Analyst** 01.2013 – 01.2023

Used a data-driven approach to manage and improve software teams, products and processes in the company.

- Acting as a Growth Hacking master and analyst, helped product owners invent, run and measure a series of
  experiments aimed to increase customer acquisition. As a result, we found a few new entry points providing
  an additional 30% of new visitors every month.
- Wrote SQL queries for analytical tasks to help product owners get deeper insights into products, made their decision-making informed-based, and triangulate new product ideas and hypotheses. It allowed to discard of 30% of valueless product ideas and save the development team time.
- Conducted exhaustive data analysis to assess the effectiveness of the forecast estimation method in use. It gave valuable insights, which helped me to revise the method and improve the dev phase forecasting accuracy from 50% to 85%.
- Collected and thoroughly analyzed statistics of product team impediments based on data from Jira, which helped to reveal and then eliminate several system obstacles, thus resulting in the increase of flow efficiency from 65% to 90% and faster feature delivery.
- Designed and programmed a series of team performance-related reports and chatbots for Slack, such as quarterly productivity, individual performance, an electronic burndown, and auto-notifications on overdue tasks. They reduced 3x research time, significantly improved transparency, fastened development by 1.5x, and, therefore, became widely adopted in the company by project managers and dev teams.

<u>Softline Group</u> (global IT service provider with 10,000+ employees, 60,000+ customers, 3,000+ tech vendors, operations in 50+ countries and \$1.5+ billion in total sales in 2022)

Novosibirsk, Russia

Head of web development 08.2010 - 12.2012

**Project manager** 05.2009 – 08.2010

**Positive Solutions** 

Novosibirsk, Russia

**Analyst** 06.2008 – 03.2009

<u>Parallels</u> (leader in the virtualization and automation software industry, partnerships with Microsoft, Apple, and Google, millions of users worldwide, presence in 125+ countries)

Novosibirsk, Russia

**Technical writer** 09.2006 – 06.2008

<u>Acronis</u> (global technology company specializing in cyber protection solutions, 2000+ employees, 500,000+ business customers, presence in 150+ countries)

Novosibirsk, Russia

Technical support engineer 01.2006 – 08.2006

## **Education**

Siberian State Transport University, Novosibirsk, Russia, 2001-2006

Master's degree in *Information Systems and Technologies*, diploma with honors